We’re trying to please Guru and Vaiṣṇava.
نحن نحاول إرضاء المعلم والڤايشناڤ.
[Dress for Kṛṣṇa]
[إلبسوا لكريشنا]
Like Avadhūt Mahārāj was once telling,
مثل ما قال آڤادوت مهاراج في مره من المرات،
in the Russian circus there’s always a bear
يوجد دائماً في السيرك الروسي الدب
who rides a bicycle, or a unicycle or something like that
الذي يركب الدرّاجة، أو الدرّاجة ذات العجلة الواحده، أو شيء كهذا،
—not that that’s the only thing, but that’s kind of standard,
ليس هذا الشيء الوحيد، ولكن من هذا النوع المعتاد،
there should be a bear riding a bicycle.
يجب أن يكون هناك دب يركب درّاجة…
So Avadhūt Mahārāj said humbly when he took sannyās,
لذلك قال آڤادوت مهاراج، بتواضع، عندما قبِل بالسنياس،
“If I’m like the Russian bear riding the bicycle
"إذا أكون مثل الدب الروسي الذي يركب درّاجة
for the amusement of Gurudev, then that’s my happiness.”
لتسلية غوروديف، إذآً فهذه سعادتي."
He was saying it humbly, “Is this not comical?
كان يقول ذلك بكل تواضع، "أليست هذه مضحكه؟
But if it gives my Gurudev happiness,
ولكن إذا كانت تسعد غوروديڤ،
So who are we concerned about?
إذاً بمن نهتم؟
Who are we concerned what we look like to?
‎من يهمنا كيف نبدو لهم؟
The people of the world, or Guru and Vaiṣṇava?
شعوب العالم، أو الغورو والڤايشناڤ؟
Gopīs decorate themselves, they make themselves look nice for Kṛṣṇa.
بنات الغوپي ‪(‬gopis‪)‬ يتزيّن، و يجعلن مظهرهن جميل لكريشنا.
I always have a running dialog, “Do women make themselves look nice
لدي دائما حِوار مستمر، "هل النساء يزيّن أنفسهم
for men or for other women?”
للرجال أو لغيرهن من النساء؟"
One week it’s for men, one week it’s for other women,
أسبوع للرجال، وأسبوع لغيرهن من النساء،
and it will go on until the end of time,
وهذا سيستمر إلى الانهاية،
this all-important dialog.
هذا الجوار البالغ الأهمية.
But what we’re told is, the Vraja-gopīs,
ولكن ما يقال لنا، إن الڤْراچا غوپي،
they make themselves look nice for Kṛṣṇa.
إنهن يجعلن مظهرهن جميل لكريشنا.
That’s why.
هذا هو السبب.
And that’s a very beautiful thing,
وهذا شيء جميل جداً،
so they’re dressing nicely.
لهذا يلبسن الملابس الجميله.